Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
I'm Always Watching
((オビト：なんだよ　ミナト先生。
俺たちを呼んどいて遅刻かよ。
What the hell...
Minato Sensei tells us to assemble
and he's the one who's late!
しようがねえな。
Give me a break...
（カカシ）お前が言うか。
なにを！？
You're one to talk!
What did you say?
ああん！？
（リン）まあまあ２人とも。
Eh?
Come on, you two...
やんのか　コラ！
フンッ。
Want to do this?
あっ　テメエ今　鼻で笑いやがったな。
だから　どうした？
Hey! Did you just scoff at me?
What of it?
（ミナト）お待たせ
みんな集まってるね。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You're all here, I see.
ミナト先生！　新しい任務ですか？
Minato Sensei!
Do we have a new mission?!
今日は違うんだ。
Not today.
なんだそれ？
What is that?
志願書だ。
キミたちを中忍に推薦しておいた。
They're applications.
I recommended you three
for promotion to Chunin.
ミナト先生　大好きだよ！
Minato Sensei... You're awesome!
おっと！　気が早いよ。
Hey...
Don't jump the gun.
え？
中忍になるためには試験がある。
Huh?
You have to take
the Chunin Exam first.
え～。
What...
試験は一次　二次　三次とあって
それぞれ　かなりの難関だ。
There are three parts
to the exam
and each one is quite difficult.
チェッ　そうなのか。
Oh... Are you kidding me?
待ち合わせの時刻ひとつ守れない
お前には無理かもな。
You'll never pass since
you can't even make it
to a rendezvous on time.
なんだと！
ちょっと２人とも。
What did you say?!
Hey, you two!
とはいえ　ともに任務を務め→
Anyway...
You've worked together
中忍試験を受ける資格があると
認めたから推薦したんだ。
and earned the right to take
the Chunin Exam.
That's why I recommended you.
ただし　中忍試験は強制ではない。
However, it's not compulsory.
受験するしないは
自分で決めなさい。
Whether you take the exam
or not is entirely up to you.
フフンッ。
もちろん！
I wouldn't miss it...!
CHUNIN EXAM
PART ONE
《なんだよ！
中忍試験っていうから→
Aw man!
This is a Chunin Exam,
忍術か体術かと思ってたら→
so I was expecting stuff like
ninjutsu and taijutsu...
俺のいちばん苦手な
ペーパーテストかよ！》
But this is a written test...
the kind I'm weakest in!
もう終わったのか？
（カカシ）はい。
Finished already?
Yes.
《カ…　カカシのヤツ！
Th-That Kakashi...!
あぁっ！　もうダメだ！》
Aw man, I'm done for...
Huh?!
I'M ALWAYS WATCHING YOU
-RIN
《リン…》
Rin...
キャー！
私　あった！
RIN NOHARA
あった！
やった！
There it is!
I did it!
う…。
KAKASHI HATAKE
（カカシ）まっ　当然でしょ。
Well...
What did you expect?
フンッ！　所詮ペーパーテストじゃねえか！
That was just a written test!
見てろ！　すぐに俺の名前も
見つかるっての！
Just wait and see!
I'll find my name!
END OF LIST
ダメか…。
I guess not...
あっ　オビト！　あれあれ！
Obito!
Look! There!
THE FOLLOWING HAS BEEN
ACCEPTED DUE TO A VACANCY
OBITO UCHIHA
やった～！
補欠合格か。
I did it!
A vacancy, huh...
That's so like you.
オビトらしいな。
なんだと！？
What?!
まあまあ　２人とも。
Come on, you two.
喜んでる暇はねえぜ。
You don't have time
to celebrate!
合格者は　指定の教室に。
If you passed,
go to your assigned classroom!
第二次試験の説明をする。
We'll explain the second part
of the exam.
二次試験は３日後。
Part Two will commence
three days from now.
今度の試験は　実技テストだ。
This will test your physical skills.
お前たちが体得している
体術　忍術のすべてを使い→
Use everything you learned
about taijutsu and ninjutsu...
合格を勝ち取るのだ。
to get through this exam!
よ～し　もらったぜ！
All right! I got this!
ただし　これは
班別の団体対抗戦とする。
However, this test pits
your team against others.
えっ！？　個人戦じゃないのか。
Huh? It's not
an individual competition?!
カカシ　俺たちの足を
引っぱるんじゃねえぜ。
Kakashi! You'd better not
drag us down!
はぁ…。
その言葉
そのままお前に返してやる。
Right back at you.
なに！？
フン。
What?!
２人とも　いい加減にして！
Will you two stop it?!
特に　遅刻するんじゃないぞ。
Especially... don't be late.
フン　わかってらぁ！
I know!
CHUNIN EXAM PART TWO
TEAM COMPETITION
（ヒルゼン）はたけカカシも
受験するんだったな。
Kakashi Hatake is also
participating in the test, right?
はい　この次のチームです。
Yes, he's on the next team.
楽しみだな。
Ah, I'm looking forward to this.
KAKASHI OBITO RIN
GUY EBISU GENMA
IBIKI HAYATE TOKARA
ミナト班　あと５分で時間だが
大丈夫なのか？
Team Minato,
you have five minutes left.
Will he make it?!
はい。
もうすぐ到着すると思います。
Yes! I'm sure he'll be here
in a minute.
もし試験時間に遅れたら
その時点で失格とする。
If time runs out,
you'll be automatically disqualified.
ほらな　俺が言ったとおりだろ。
I knew it! Didn't I tell you?!
リンが甘やかすから
アイツの遅刻グセは直んないんだよ。
You're too easy on him, Rin.
That's why he'll never break
this habit of being late!
大丈夫だよ。　きっと何か大事な
用事があって遅くなってるだけ。
He'll be here.
Something must've happened
to delay him.
試験時間には　間に合うから。
He'll make it in time.
フン　それはどうかな。
I wouldn't be so sure.
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
はい　飴ちゃんじゃ。
Here, have some candy.
午後３時…　試験開始時間だ。
3:00 pm.
It's time to begin.
クソッ　アイツのせいで…。
Damn it, all because of him!
必ず…。
I know he'll...
遅くなりました！
I'm sorry I'm late!
ほら　オビトは
絶対　来るって言ったでしょ。
See! I told you Obito would make it,
no matter what!
急げ　失格になるぞ。
Hurry, before we're disqualified!
ハァー　ったく。
Oh, boy!
これより　第二次班対抗戦
一次予選を開始する。
We will now begin part two,
the team competition...
Preliminary qualifier!
はじめ！
Begin!
（ガイ）うお～っ！
《火遁　豪火球の…》
Fire Style! Fireball—
CHUNIN EXAM PART THREE
INDIVIDUAL COMPETITION
この間のお返しは
たっぷりさせてもらうからな！
I'm going to have you pay me back
in full for the last time.
この間って…。
The "last time"?
なに！？　まさか覚えてねえのか？
What?!
Don't tell me
you don't remember?!
誰だ　お前は！
恨みをかうような覚えはない！
Who are you?
What did I do to earn
your wrath?!
この～！　バカにしやがって！
Why you—!
Don't take me for a fool!
（リン）頑張って！　オビト！
Do your best, Obito!
よ～し　見ててくれ！
All right... Just watch me!
始め！
えっ？
Begin!
Huh?!
ホアチャー！
勝者　マイト・ガイ！
The winner is Might Guy!
何やってんだか…。
What is he doing?
ぐわっ！
頑張れ！
Do your best!
いけ～！　カカシ！
Go...!
Kakashi!
そこまで！　勝者　はたけカカシ！
Stop!
The winner is Kakashi Hatake!
やった！
He did it!
一発で中忍試験をクリアするなんて
やっぱりカカシは　すごいよ！
You passed the Chunin Exam
on your first try.
Kakashi, you're amazing!
Isn't he, Obito?
ねっ　オビト！
フン！
あっ…。
Humph.
オビト…。
Obito...
（オビト）はぁ…。
こんなとこにいたんだ！
So this is where you were.
うわっ…　なんだ　リンか。
O-Oh, it's you, Rin.
カカシが受かるのは当然だけど
私たちもできるよ　きっと！
It's only natural
that Kakashi passed.
But we can too, I know it!
来年の試験　頑張りましょ！
Let's practice hard
for next year!
でもよ　カカシ見てると
なんだか　やる気が出なくて。
But it's hard to get motivated
after watching Kakashi...
なに言ってるの！
What are you saying?!
火影になるんでしょ。
You're going to be Hokage, right?
私が　ちゃんと見てるから！
I'm always watching you!
(ああ！))
Yeah!
Obito?
((オビト？
I did it!
やったぜ！　俺も中忍だ！
I'm a Chunin now!
Congratulations!
おめでとう！
フン！
Meet me later at the park
under the cherry tree.
あとで公園の桜の木の下に来て。
Today for sure...
《今日こそ　リンに
俺の本当の気持を…》
I'm going to tell Rin
how I feel about her!
遅れて　ごめ～ん！
いやいや…。
Sorry I'm late...
– No...
– Everyone!
みんな！
みんな？
Everyone?
え？
Why? Uh, Why...
なんで？
Why is everyone here?!
なんで　みんな　いるんだよ？
お祝いの相談をするから
集まってもらったの。
I asked them to come
to discuss the gift.
Huh? What gift?!
えっ　お祝いの相談って？
Well, Kakashi is being promoted
to Jonin.
今度　カカシが上忍に
就任するでしょ？
So, we're going to...
give him a present.
だから　同期のみんなで何か
プレゼントしようって。
CLASS PROJECT
GIFT FOR KAKASHI'S PROMOTION
TO JONIN
(TOP SECRET MISSION)
Kakashi's a Jonin?
カカシが上忍に？
Oh? Didn't you know, Obito?
あれ　オビト知らなかったの？
同期の私たちにとっても→
It's something to be proud of
as his classmates.
自慢のたねでしょ。
は　はぁ…。
Yeah...
What do you think
Kakashi would like?
ねぇ　何したら　カカシ喜ぶと思う？
Well... Since we're talking about him,
そうねぇ　アイツのことだから…。
it should be
something useful.
Now we'll do combat training.
これから行うのは実戦訓練だ。
訓練だからと油断していると
命にもかかわる。
It might just be training,
but if you're not alert,
it can be fatal. Understood?
いいね？
（３人）はい！
– Yes!
あっ！　いや　まぁ…
ざっと　こんなもんさ。
Well... I guess that's it!
左手　みせて。
Show me your left hand!
いやぁ　こんなの
どうってことねえから。
Hey, it's nothing...
It's just a scrape.
ただのかすり傷だから
ツバつけとけば治るって。
A little spit will take care of it.
いいから　みせなさい！
Whatever! Just show me!
I messed up...
ちょっと　ヘマしちまった。
I got some sand in my eyes and...
目に砂が入っちまって…。
ハハッ！　男にゃ　傷の一つや二つ→
A scar or two on a man
is a badge of courage!
体に刻んどかなきゃ
はくがつかねえし→
I was just thinking how
I needed that.
ちょうど　はくをつけとく
頃合いだと思ってよ。
だから　こんな傷…。
So this wound's...
Ouch!
痛っ！！
（リン）強がって傷を隠しても　ダメ。
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
ちゃんと見てんだから。
I'm always watching you.
オビトは　火影になるって
私に約束した。
You promised me that you would
become Hokage, Obito.
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
いい？
私だって　この戦争を止めたい。
世界を救いたいと
本気で思ってるよ。
I really want to save the world.
だから　オビトのこと　そばで
しっかり見守るって決めたの。
So I decided to stick by your side
and watch over you.
あなたを救うことは
世界を救うのと同じなんでしょ？
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
うん…。
Yeah...
Since I'm keeping an eye on you,
私が見張ってるってことは→
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
もう　なんにも
隠し事はできないよ。
Okay! Okay!
うん…　うん…。
（リン）頑張れ　オビト！
Go for it, Obito!
火影になって　かっこよく
世界を救うとこ見せてね！
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
それも約束だよ。
That's another promise!
Let's go!
(行こう))
You...
（ナルト）お前　仲間の思いや思い出を
全部　捨てるって→
You told Kakashi Sensei
you would throw away
all your memories and feelings
about your comrades.
カカシ先生に言ってたみてぇだけど→
But when you became
the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki
十尾の人柱力になって　ソイツに
乗っ取られそうになったとき…。
and were about to
be taken over by it...
((オビト：あ～っ！))
Didn't you try to suppress
the Ten Tails
それが嫌で　十尾を押さえ込もうと
したんじゃねえのかよ？
because you didn't want that?
((うわぁ！！))
十尾に勝って
それを自分で操れたのは→
The reason why you beat
the Ten Tails and could control it
was because you stood firm
on not throwing away the past
今までのことを
捨てたくねえって→
踏ん張って
自分のままでいたからだろ。
and stayed yourself, right?
お前　やっぱり
父ちゃんも　カカシ先生も→
You just couldn't throw out
the memories of
my dad, Kakashi Sensei or
this Rin person, could you?
リンって人の思い出も
捨てられなかったんじゃねえのか。
だから　十尾の人柱力になっても→
That's how you could stay Obito
even after you became
the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki.
オビトのままでいられたんだろう？
違うかよ？
Am I wrong?
But dragging everyone with you
onto your path
けど　みんなを巻き込んで→
お前の道を
このまま突き進むのは→
and continuing on it
won't be allowed!
許されることじゃねえ！
I'm bringing you back
as Obito Uchiha...
こっちの道へ来て
うちはオビトとして→
as a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf...
木ノ葉の忍として
きっちり罪を償ってもらう。
and you're going to atone
for your sins.
You tried to run away
from every single thing.
何もかもから
逃げようとしやがって！
The only thing that awaits you...
((その先に待っているのは
お前も　よく知る→
is your personal nightmare.
最も恐ろしい…。
Solitude!
孤独だ！
現実にいる必要が　どこにある？
So why keep living in reality?
(いい加減　こっちへ来い　ナルト！))
Now come join us, Naruto!
I bet this Rin person would say this
if she were still alive...
リンって人が生きてたら
きっと　こう言っただろうな。
強がって自分を隠すなって。
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
I'm always watching.
ちゃんと見てんだからってよ。
お前は　お前だ　この野郎！
You're no one else but you,
damn it!
Don't run away!
逃げんな！
Come join us...
お前こそ　こっちへ来い！
Obito!
オビト！
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
sugu wasurechatte dame da
It's not good that I'm so forgetful
uzukumattecha dame da
It's not good that I'm cowering
kizutsuitatte ana aitatte
Even if I'm wounded and pierced
massugu tatteirareruyou ni naritai
I want to be able to stand up straight
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
I will never go over to your side!
I have no regrets with
my path up until now.
I told you I saw everything.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Then don't keep imagining
yourself as Hokage!
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
The person Rin wanted to
watch over isn't the current you...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Promise That Was Kept"
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
It was Obito Uchiha!
（松丸）今回は特別に
島倉千代子さんの→
ヒットメドレーからスタートします。